Guide to the School of Architecture, Yale University, Records Concerning Retrospecta
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Architecture, Yale University, records concerning Retrospecta
2005-2006
RU 1018
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
1 box
29593.6
The records consist of digital images, text, and video and audio recordings used in the publication of Retrospecta.
Yale University. School of Architecture
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 19-E (YRG 19-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Architecture.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Yale School of Architecture, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Biographical / Historical
Retrospecta is an annual journal edited by architecture students and published by the Yale School of Architecture. The primary focus of the journal is student work, but activities of the School of Architecture are also covered.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of digital images, text, and video and audio recordings used in the publication of Retrospecta.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by topic.
Retrospecta; Architecture; College publications; Born digital; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Architecture
- Records of activities used to create Retrospecta, 2005-2006; Accession 2007-A-095
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2042.
  - Students' Work (Fall), 2006 May 14; 1,873 computer files (DOC, TIFF)
    - 501a First Year Design Studio
      - Students
        - Arena
        - Field
          - Closing
            General note
            Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
        - Form
          - Students
        - Surface
    - 503a Second Year Design Studio
      - Students
        - Critic Claire Weisz
        - Critic Keith Kruwiede
        - Critic Martin Finio
        - Critic Peter de Bretteville
    - 509a Post-Pro Design Studio
      - Students
    - 511a Advance Design Studio - Krier
      - Students
    - 513a Advance Design Studio - Murcutt
      - students
        - Closing Remarks Murcutt Transcription, computer file (DOC)
  - Students' Work (Fall), 2006 May 14; 2,163 computer files (DOC, TIFF)
    - 515a Advance Design Studio - Shim
      - Archive
        - 515a Shim Studio Complete Text, computer file (DOC)
      - Students
        - Closing Remarks Transcription, computer file (DOC)
      - 515a Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 515a Shim Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
    - 517a Advance Design Studio - Eisenman
      - Archive
        - 517a Eisenman Studio Complete Text, computer file (DOC)
        - 517a Eisenman Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - Recordings
      - Students
      - 517a Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 517a Eisenman Studio Complete Text_proofread_trim, computer file (DOC)
    - 519a Advance Design Studio - Gang
      - Archive
      - Students
      - Travel Photos
        - gang
      - 519a Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 519a Gang Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
    - 521a Advance Design Studio - Plattus
      - Archive
      - Students
      - Travel Photos
        - Best Photos
        - Plattus Travel Photos
      - 521a Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 521a Plattus Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
    - 523a Advance Design Studio - Sanders
      - Archive
      - Sanders Travel Photos
      - Students
      - 523a Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 523a Sanders Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
    - Studio Lottery
  - Students" Work (Fall), 2006 May 14; 3,831 computer files (DOC, TIFF, JPEG) (Box 1–8)
    - History and Theory
      - 704a Case Studies in Architectural Theory
        - Students
      - 717a Issues in Architecture and Urbanism
      - 757a The Construction of Exactitude
        - students
      - 759a Architecture Fragment and Completeness
        - students
      - 768a Writing on Architecture
        - students
      - 912a American Cultural Landscapes
        - students
      - 925a Cities, Suburbs, and the Culture of Sprawl
        - students
      - arc 757a, 2005 December 12; computer file (MP3)
    - Materials and Production
      - 625a Liquid Threshold Btw Order and Chaos
        - students
        - model failures, computer file (PPT)
      - 674a Architectural Product Design
        - Reviews Recording
        - students
      - 682a Aluminum Casting and Design
        - students
    - Urbanism and Landscape
      - 903a Intro to Planning and Development
        - Reviews Recording
      - 912a
    - Visual Presentation
      - 759a Architecture, Fragment and Completeness
        - Students
      - Drawing and Architectural Form
        - Student Work
      - Eero Saarinen
        - Students
      - Evolutionary Design and Digital Fabrication (Weinstock)
        - Students
      - Form, Shape, and the Emergence of Exoticism (Gage)
        - Student Work
      - Geometry Drawing Visual Inquiry
      - Intro to Visual Studies
        - Eisenman's 5 and 6
        - Eisenmans top 4
        - Eisenman Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - Photography for Architects
        - Student Work
    - Retrospecta 05-06 Master Schedule, computer file (XLS) (Box 1)
  - Students" Work (Spring), 2006 May 30; 1,476 computer files (DOC, TIFF, MP3)
    - 502b First Year Design Studio
      - BP individual design
      - Building project
        - Archive
        - Teams
          - Team Banana
          - Team Coconut
          - Team Mango
          - Team Papaya
          - Team Strawberry
          - Team Watermelon
        - 506b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
        - Building Project Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - Cohabitation
        - Archive
        - Recordings
          - 502 First Year Cohab sample, organshci
        - Students
        - 502b Cohabitation complete text_proofread_Trim, computer file (DOC)
      - Evacuee
        - Archive
        - Housing Final Review
          - Day 1 - Peter Amy Alan
          - Day 1- Brook Sample Gooden
          - Day 2 - Turner Hilary Alan
          - Day 2 - Peter Amy Gooden Closing
        - Housing Mid Review
          - Evacuee Housing Gooden, Organski
          - Recorder3
        - Students
          - 7_MARC_NEWMAN_MULTI UNIT
          - 10_Jeff_Geldart
          - 11_Nobuki_Ogasahara
        - 502b Evacuee Housing Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - Housing study
      - 502b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
    - 512b Lynn Studio
      - Archive
      - Final Review
      - Mid review
      - Students
      - 512b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 512b Lynn Studio Complete Text _proofread, computer file (DOC)
    - 514b Porphyrios Studio
      - Archive
      - Final review
      - Students
      - 514b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 514b Porphyrios Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - VOICE001, computer file (MP3)
      - VOICE003, computer file (MP3)
    - 518b Bruder Studio
      - Archive
      - Mid review
      - Students
      - 518b Bruder Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - 518b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
  - Students' Work (Spring), 2006 May 30; 2,352 computer files (DOC, TIFF, MP3)
    - 504b Second Year Design Studio
      - Final Review
        - 504b Monday Kahn Plattus Deamer
        - Tuesday_Petit_Mitchell
      - Mid Review
        - Monday_Petit_Kahn
        - Notes
        - Tuesday_mitchell_plattus_deamer
        - .DS_Store
      - Students
        - Deamer
          - Archive
          - 504b Deamer Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
        - Kahn
          - Archive
          - 504b Kahn Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
        - Mitchell
          - 4_Neil Weston
          - Archive
          - 504b Mitchell Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
        - Petit
          - Archive
          - 504b Petit Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
        - Plattus
          - Archive
          - 504b Plattus Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - .DS_Store
      - 504b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
    - 516b Rogers Wise Lipton Studio
      - Archive
      - Mid Review, 2006 March 2
      - Students
        - Rogers wise lipton studio picks and critic, computer file (DOC)
      - 516b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 516b Rogers Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - VOICE002, computer file (MP3)
      - VOICE003, computer file (MP3)
    - 520b Behnisch Studio
      - Archive
      - Final Review
      - Mid review
      - Students
      - 520b Behnisch Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - 520b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
    - 522b Gehry Studio
      - Archive
      - Students
      - 522b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 522b Gehry Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
    - 524b Bald Studio
      - Archive
      - Mid review
      - Students
      - 524b Bald Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
      - 524b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
    - Advanced Studio Lottery
  - Students' Work (Spring), 2006 May 30; 3,349 computer files (DOC, TIFF, MP3, HTML, JPEG)
    - 526b Krumwiede Studio
      - archive
      - mid review
      - Students
      - 526b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 526b Krumwiede Studio Complete Text_proofread, computer file (DOC)
    - 599b Thesis
    - Building Technology and Practice
      - 635b Exploring Glass
        - Students
      - 648b System Integration
        - 648b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 681b Furniture Design and Fabrication
    - History and Theory
      - 748b Gross Domestic Product
      - 750b Architectural Multiplications
      - 760b Critical Architecture
      - 777b Kahn in Context
      - 778b Architecture and the Unmaking of Nations
      - 789b Making Sense
    - Materials and Production
      - 661b Materials and Morphology
      - 688b Ornament and Technology
    - MED
      - MED Colloquium
        - Archive
        - Recordings
        - Colloquium_syllabus_v7, computer file (PDF)
        - MED Colloquium Course Description, computer file (DOC)
        - MED Colloquium Text for Publication_revised, computer file (DOC)
      - Students
        - 1st year
        - 2nd year
      - Thesis Presentation Recording
        - Recordings
      - MED Thesis Presentation, computer file (DOC)
    - Rome
      - Students
      - Travel Photo
      - 791c Course Description, computer file (DOC)
    - Urbanism and Landscape
      - 905b Planning and Development
      - 914b Built Environments and the Politics of Place
    - Visual Presentation
      - 804b Drawing Projects
      - 808b Freehand Drawing
      - 811b Classical Drawing
      - 813b Photography for Architects
      - 814b Advanced Photography for Architects
      - 828b Atmosphere and Effect
        - 828b Course Description, computer file (DOC)
      - 860b Web Design for Architects
        - Students
  - Fall Recordings, 2006 May 14; 315
    - Accounting
    - Courses_Fall 2005
      - 501a First Year Design Studio
        - Review Recordings
          - 501 a Final Review
            - 501a Final Review Monday 12-05-2005
              - Blood, Mimi, Pell
              - Keller, Gage, Gavin
            - 501a Final Review Tuesday 12-06-2005
              - Easterling Pell Hoang
              - Hogben Gage Blood
          - 501 a Review I
          - 501 a Review II
            - 501a Review II 10-3-2005
              - East
              - West
            - 501a Review II 10-4-2005
              - West
            - 501a Review II Audio Files TO BE SORTED
          - 501a Review III
            - 501a Review III 10-25
              - 501a Review III 10-25 4th Floor West
            - First year form 102405-Erica
            - First year form 102405-Ravi
            - First year form 102505 Keller Gage Mimi
      - 503a Second Year Design Studio
        - Photos
        - Reviews Recording
          - 503a Final Review
            - Tuesday_Keith and Clara
            - Tuesday_Peterand Martin
            - Wednesday_Clara and Peter afternoon
            - Wednesday_Clara and Peter morning
            - Wednesday_Keith and Martin
            - 503a Final Review Tuesday Closing, computer file (MP3)
            - 503a Final Review Tuesday Opening.WMA
            - 503a Final Review Wednesday Closing2, computer file (MP3)
            - 503a Final Review Wednesday Closing, computer file (MP3)
            - 503a Final Review Wednesday opening, computer file (MP3)
          - 503a Mid-Review
      - 509a Post-Pro Design Studio
        - Reviews Recording
          - 509a Final Review Audio Files
          - 509a Mid-Review Audio Files To BE SORTED
            - Post-pro audio
      - 511a Advance Design Studio - Krier
        - Reviews Recording
          - 511a Final Review Krier, 2005 December 9
      - 511a Mid-Review Audio Files To BE SORTED
        - Krier
      - 513a Advance Design Studio - Murcutt
        - Reviews Recording
          - 513a Final review
          - 513a Mid-Review Audio Files To BE SORTED
            - Murcutt
      - 515a Advance Design Studio - Shim
        - Reviews Recording
          - 515a Mid-Review Audio Files To BE SORTED
      - 517a Advance Design Studio - Eisenman
        - Reviews Recording
          - 517a Final Review
      - 519a Advance Design Studio - Gang
        - Reviews Recording
          - 519a Final Review
          - 519a Mid-Review Audio Files To BE SORTED
            - Gang studio
      - 521a Advance Design Studio - Plattus
        - Reviews Recording
          - 521a Final Review Audio Files
          - 521a Mid-Review Audio Files To BE SORTED
      - 523a Advance Design Studio - Sanders
        - Reviews Recording
          - 523a Final Review
          - 523a Mid-Review Audio Files To BE SORTED
          - Balmouri
      - MED Finals, 2005 December 12
      - Studio Lottery
      - Undergraduate
        - 249a Analytical Model (Petit)
        - Junior studio
        - Methods and Form in Architecture
      - Unknown recordings
        - Grey Recorder
        - VOICE002, computer file (MP3)
      - Arc 757a, 2005 December 12; computer file (MP3)
    - Documentation
      - Archive
      - Correspondences
      - Dean's letter
      - Forms
      - Retrospecta Directory, 2005-2006; computer file (XLS)
      - Retrospecta Fall Transcription Assignment, 2005-2006; computer file (PDF)
      - Retrospecta Master Schedule, 2005-2006; computer file (XLS)
    - Lectures_Fall 2005
      - Forster Lecture Images, 2005-2006
  - Spring Recordings, 2006; 278 computer files (WAV, MP3)
    - 502b First Year Design Studio
      - Cohabitation
        - Recordings
          - 502 First Year Cohab sample, organshci
      - Housing
        - Housing Final Review
          - Day 1 - Peter Amy Alan
          - Day 1- Brook Sample Gooden
          - Day 2 - Turner Hilary Alan
          - Day 2 - Peter Amy Gooden Closing
        - Housing Mid Review
    - 504 Second Year Design Studio
      - Final Review
        - 504b Monday Kahn Plattus Deamer
        - Tuesday_Petit_Mitchell
      - Mid Review
        - Monday_Petit_Kahn
        - Notes
        - Tuesday_mitchell_plattus_deamer
        - .DS_Store
    - 512b Lynn Studio
      - Final Review
      - Mid review
    - 514b Porphyrios Studio
      - Final review
    - 516b Rogers Wise Lipton Studio
      - Final Review
      - Mid Review, 2006 March 2
    - 518b Bruder Studio
      - Mid review
    - 520b Behnisch Studio
      - Final Review
      - Mid review
    - 522b Gehry Studio
    - 524b Bald Studio
    - 526b Krumwiede Studio
      - Final Review
      - Mid review
    - 599b Thesis
    - Advanced Studio Lottery
    - Lectures_Spring 2006
    - Undergraduate
      - Junior studio
      - Senior studio